Nicole: As we have already discussed
written communications can take
different forms and may involve
reports, policy documents even
emails and instruction manuals.
The way written communications are
put together and the tone used to
impart the information, are important
and should be set at a level that the
different audiences reading them can
understand for them to be effective.
Let's look at some of the elements that
make written communications effective.
Abraham: Written communication should have
a clear purpose and should not be vague.
The purpose should be clearly stated
at the beginning of the communication
defining what it wants to achieve.
The reader knows what they are reading
about straight away about without
having to wade through ramblings.
A good example of this would be
documenting a threat and clearly
putting together a report on
any imminent threat attacks.
Nicole: Not only should it be
clear about the purpose the message
behind the written communication
should be clear what the goal is.
An example of a clear message would be
to ensure that a team understands what
is expected and can align themselves with
that goal such as being aware of any cyber
security protocols related to current
activities or future threat actors.
Abraham: It is important that
written communication is accurate
so that people reading it can have
confidence on any data displayed.
This is really important when
creating manuals or giving directions
to other members of a team.
Nicole: Attention to detail means
that all the information needed is
contained in the written communication
and the reader doesn't have to look
elsewhere for further clarification.
This can also help give clear guidance
that’s easy to follow in manuals and
instruction booklets prevent mistakes
being made or misunderstandings.
Abraham: The correct use of spelling,
grammar and punctuation are very
important as errors can change
the meaning of a message which
might result in misinformation.
Correct usage also gives the reader more
confidence in the communication and more
likely to act on the information imparted.
Nicole: The 'tone of voice'
of the written communication
should be right for the audience
concerned, so that it communicates
how it should be responded to.
If the tone is too relaxed it won’t
communicate any urgency that maybe
involved in the communication.
Abraham: The written communication
should have an appropriate layout
which makes it clearer to read
and understand the key points.
It can also make it easier to
find the appropriate sections
within the communication.
This is especially important
when putting reports together
Nicole: So, we can see how the skill
of written communication is really
important as cyber security professionals
need to make sure that they are
on the same page with their team.
They also often need to communicate
with everyone else in a company or
organisation and are responsible for
sharing important information with
people who aren’t well versed in the
technical jargon and language of cyber
security, so being mindful about how they
communicate can make all the difference.